SEAN DILLON

25200 Wilson St., Los Molinos, CA, USA 96055 530 591 3550 \$\prec\$ smdillon@mail.csuchico.edu

SUMMARY

I am a 22-year-old student at California State University - Chico, majoring in Physics and minoring in Mathematics. I started out my college career at University of California - Santa Cruz, which I enrolled in directly after high school where I graduated as Class Valedictorian. I chose to leave UCSC after I realized that there was no way I could graduate in 4 years without gaining massive amounts of student loan debt. I then decided to attend Butte College to fulfill the rest of my lower-division general education requirements before enrolling at California State University - Chico.

I have always strived to challenge myself with rigorous courseloads, even if it meant grades that were not exemplary. I believe that knowing how to find the information I need is a far-better skill to have than being able to take a timed test without notes. I take pride in my ability to pursue research opportunities, as well as my skills in computational physics.

I wish to go into the field of Astronomy and/or Astrophysics because I believe that I could greatly contribute to the field with my research. I excel at computational physics and using python which, when combined with my lifelong love of the stars and the night sky, would be valuable towards any research in Astrophysics.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science in Physics with a Minor in Mathematics California State University, Chico GPA: 3.09/4.00	2018 - 2020
Butte Community College GPA: 3.02/4.00	2017 - 2018
University of California, Santa Cruz GPA: 3.09/4.00	2015 - 2017
Member of Society of Physics Students Member of American Physics Society Member of American Astronomical Society	2018 - present 2018 - present 2018 - present

COURSEWORK

Grade	Course								
Mathematics	tics								
A-	Calculus for Scientists and Engineers A								
В	Calculus for Scientists and Engineers B								
	Calculus, Rogawski, 2nd Ed.								
\mathbf{C}	Vector Calculus A								
$\mathbf{C}+$	Vector Calculus B								
	Vector Calculus, Marsden/Tromba, 6th Ed.								
В	Elementary Differential Equation								
ъ	A First Course in Differential Equations, Zill, 5th Ed.								
	II I wist Course on Defferences Equations, Zool, John Eta.								
\mathbf{C}	Linear Algebra								
	Linear Algebra and its Applications, Lay, 5th Ed.								
В-	Partial Differential Equations								
Ь	Fourier Series and Boundary Value Problems, Brown/Churchill, 8th Ed.								
	Tourier period and Doubleady False Treatment, Droubly enterently continued								
Computation									
В	Introduction to Python								
	Think Python: How to Think Like A Computer Scientist, Downey, Version 2.0.17								
A-	Computational Physics								
	Computational Physics, Newman								
Spring 2020	Advanced Computational Physics								
D									
$Physics \ { m C}$	Introduction to Physics A								
B-	Introduction to Physics A Lab								
В	Introduction to Physics B								
B+	Introduction to Physics B Lab								
$\mathbf{B}^{'}$	Introduction to Physics C								
A-	Introduction to Physics C Lab								
	Physics for Scientists and Engineers, Giancolli, 4th Ed.								
\mathbf{A}	Success in Physics								
В	Introduction to Modern Physics								
<u>.</u>	Modern Physics, Harris, 2nd Ed.								
	12000 1.090000, 1201100, 2000 201								
${f C}$	Thermal Physics								
	Thermal Physics, Baierlein								

In Progress Quantum Mechanics A Spring 2020 Quantum Mechanics B

Introduction to Quantum Mechanics, Griffiths, 2nd/3rd Ed.

In Progress Analytical Mechanics A

Classical Mechanics, Taylor

C Electricity and Magnetism A In Progress Electricity and Magnetism B

Introduction to Electrodynamics, Griffiths, 4th Ed.

C Electronics for Scientists

Electronics with Discrete Components, Galvez

In Progress Advanced Laboratory

An Introduction to Error Analysis, Taylor, 2nd Ed.

Science Ed.

In Progress Learning Assistant Training

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools LabVIEW (moderate-beginner)

Platforms MS Office, Mathematica, Python 3.x+ (advanced)

PUBLICATIONS

The Sixteenth Data Release of the Sloan Digital Sky Surveys: Final release from the Extended Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey, and First Release from APOGEE-2S Masters, et. al., Published to arXiv on 12/9/19, submitted to ApJS

HI-MaNGA: Data Release 2 Stark, et. al., In Progress

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Talks 2019 APS Far West Section Meeting at Stanford University

A Principle Component Analysis of the HI Mass Fraction of Galaxies in the MaNGA Survey

2019 Keck Northeast Astronomy Consortium at Vassar College

A Principle Component Analysis of the HI Mass Fraction of Galaxies in the MaNGA Survey

Posters 2020 Winter AAS Meeting in Honolulu, Hawai'i

A Principle Component Analysis of the HI Mass Fraction of Galaxies in the MaNGA Survey

2019 College of Natural Sciences Poster Session

Modeling Convection in Slowly Rotating Sun-like Stars

INTERNSHIP/RESEARCH

Summer REU Astronomy Internship at Haverford College PHYS 499 Undergraduate Research at California State University - Chico Present May-August 2019 August 2018 -

CLUBS AND ORGANIZATIONS

American Astronomical Society

American Physical Society

Society of Physics Students

September 2018 - Present September

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tutor

October 2017 - July 2018; August 2018 - Present

I was hired as a math tutor at Butte College's Center for Academic Success, where I held drop-in tutoring hours for students needing assistance in Math courses ranging from Introductory Algebra and Pre-Calculus to Linear Algebra and Differential Equations. After enrolling at California State University - Chico, I was able to volunteer my time to hold drop-in tutoring with the Society of Physics Students. I was responsible for developing teaching methods to help students understand college-level mathematics, keeping records of tutoring sessions and suggesting strategies for improvement, promoting alternate resources to assist student achievement, and motivating older students who were re-entering education after taking extensive leaves.

Grader October 2017 - Present

I started as a grader for a College Algebra course at Butte College before coming to Chico State and grading papers for various lower-division physics courses, both algebra-based (for non-Physics/Engineering majors) as well as calculus-based. I was responsible for determining earned scores on tests and homework, ensuring mathematical techniques were being used correctly in solving problems, analyzing homework quality, and ensuring that any questions I had regarding the homework were quickly addressed with the instructor

Learning Assistant

August 2019 - Present

I was employed as a Learning Assistant(LA) for a lower-division, algebra-based mechanics course at the start of the Fall 2019 semester. Next semester, I will be an LA for a lower-division, calculus-based mechanics course. My responsibilities include attending all class-meetings, helping students who require assistance, monitoring classroom activities, as well as enrolling in a 2-unit Science Education Pedagogy class which provides opportunities to understand how best to help students in lower-division science courses.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth 2 May 1997 Address 25200 Wilson St.

Los Molinos, CA, USA, 96055

Languages known English

DECLARATION

T	hereby	dec	lare	that	above	provided	informa	tion	is	true to	hest	α f	mv	knowl	edo	re l	hel	ief	•
1	nereny	ucci	are	011a0	above	provided	morma	UUII	TO.	uue w	Dest	OI	III.y	KHOW	.cus	50 I	OCI	101	. •

Place : Date :

SEAN MICHAEL DILLON